Guide to the New-York Historical Society Celebratory and Memorial Event Records 1854-1954 NYHS-RG 12
New-York Historical Society
- N-YHS Centennial Medal. Correspondence. Subscribers (3 of 5), 1905 January-June (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
- N-YHS Centennial Medal. Correspondence. Subscribers (4 of 5), 1905 September-1906 May (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
- N-YHS Centennial Medal. Correspondence (Postcards). Subscribers (5 of 5), 1905-1906 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
- N-YHS Centennial Medal. Subscriber Lists, 1904-1906 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
- N-YHS Centennial Medal. Register of Correspondents(?), 1904 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
- N-YHS Centennial History. Announcement Cards, 1905 December (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, Alphabetical (1 of 5), 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1)
  This set of five folders includes correspondence originally arranged in alphabetical order. Generally, this is by correspondent but related matters are held together as noted by summary notations on the reverse of each letter, which is a distinguishing characteristic of all the correspondence in these five folders. It is possible that this set of correspondence was maintained by N-YHS President Samuel V. Hoffman, who is the dominant addressee or signatory of the letters. Several of the correspondents and related subjects are also found in the second set of correspondence below.
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, Alphabetical (2 of 5), 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 2)
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, Alphabetical (3 of 5), 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
  This folder includes a list (L) of objects promised to the exhibition and minutes (M) of two meetings of N-YHS officers, including Samuel Hoffman, with the Committee of the Colonial Dames of America, including Alice Crary Sutcliffe.
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, Alphabetical (4 of 5), 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, Alphabetical (5 of 5), 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 5)
  Includes Alice Crary Sutcliffe.
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, General (1 of 3), 1909-1912 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
  This second set of correspondence was originally apart from the above set, and may have been a file of Librarian Robert Kelby. There is no definitive overall order to the documents, but it appears that this first folder includes correspondence with the Hudson-Fulton Celebration Commission on various matters, including the donation of the Commission's records to N-YHS, while the second and third folders include other correspondents, principally concerning exhibition loans. Several of the correspondents and topics also appear in the above set of correspondence.
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, General (2 of 3), 1909-1910 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
- Fulton Exhibition. Correspondence, General (3 of 3), 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 8)
- Fulton Exhibition. Reproduction Permissions, [1909] (Offsite-box 6, Folder 9)
- Fulton Exhibition. Loan Register, 1909 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
  At the back of the register is an index by lender name.
- Fulton Exhibition. Loans and Loan Returns, 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 10)
- Fulton Exhibition. Registered Mail Receipts., 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 11)
- Fulton Exhibition. Catalogue (2), 1909 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 12)
- Hudson-Fulton Reviewing Stand. Print Matter, 1909 October (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
  Includes the ticket offering circular, tickets, ticket stubs, and acknowledgement forms.
- Hudson-Fulton Reviewing Stand. Payment Lists and Seating Assignments, 1909 October (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
- Hudson-Fulton Reviewing Stand. Correspondence (1 of 2), 1909 October (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
- Hudson-Fulton Reviewing Stand. Correspondence (2 of 2), 1909 October (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
- Hudson-Fulton Reviewing Stand. Payment Enclosure, 1909 October (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
- Stokes Reception. Correspondence with Stokes, 1925-1926 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
  Includes a manuscript copy of Stokes's address.
- Stokes Reception. Invitations and Event Program, 1925 November (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
- Stokes Reception. Invitation Lists, 1925 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
- Stokes Reception. Invitation Response Cards, 1925 (Offsite-box 13, Cards -)
- Stokes Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (1 of 2), 1925 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
- Stokes Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (2 of 2), 1925 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
- Stokes Reception. Proceedings and Addresses (Print), 1925 November 17 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 11)
- Eames Reception. Invitations and Event Program, 1931 November 20 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 12)
- Eames Reception. Attendee Lists (1 of 2), 1931 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 13)
- Eames Reception. Attendee Lists (2 of 2), 1931 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 14)
- Eames Reception. Correspondence, Acceptances (1 of 2), 1931 October-November (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
- Eames Reception. Correspondence, Acceptances (2 of 2), 1931 October-November (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
- Eames Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (1 of 2), 1931 October-November (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
- Eames Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (2 of 2), 1931 October-November (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
- Eames Reception. Proceedings and Addresses (Print), 1931 November 20 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
- Lockman Reception. Invitations and Event Program, 1933 November 20 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
- Lockman Reception. Attendee Lists, 1933 (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
- Lockman Reception. Correspondence, Acceptances, 1933 November (Offsite-box 8, Folder 8)
- Lockman Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (1 of 2), 1933 November (Offsite-box 8, Folder 9)
- Lockman Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (2 of 2), 1933 November (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
- Lockman Reception. Proceedings and Addresses (Print), 1933 November 20 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
- Lectures. Correspondence (1 of 2), 1931-1934 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
  Includes marketing brochures of: speakers Charles Brook, George Francis Dow, William Osgood Field, Gilbert E. Gable, Gilbert McClurg, Harold Stark, and Fanny Washington; performers American Operatic Players, Laurance Hart (impersonating George Washington), Princess Atalie (singer), Te Ata (singer, dancer), and Lucia Gario.
- Lectures. Correspondence (2 of 2), 1933-1936 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
  Includes marketing brochures of speakers Madame Barry-Orlova, Victor Branson De Cou, William Webster Ellsworth, Charles Wellington Furlong, Ellsworth Jaeger, and various from Bralans Lecture Bureau.
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Acceptances (1 of 5), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Acceptances (2 of 5), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Acceptances (3 of 5), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Acceptances (4 of 5), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Acceptances (5 of 5), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Regrets (1 of 3), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Regrets (2 of 3), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
- CPW Opening Ceremony. Correspondence, Regrets (3 of 3), 1939 March (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
- Musicale & Strawberry Festival. Correspondence (Ticket Requests) (1 of 2), 1939 May-June (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
- Musicale & Strawberry Festival. Correspondence (Ticket Requests) (2 of 2), 1939 May-June (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
- St. Nicholas Festival. Program & "Sancte Claus, Goed Heylig Man!" facsimile score, 1939 December 6 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  This folder holds copies of the score that was originally distributed by N-YHS in December 1964; see also: New-York Historical Society manuscripts of lectures and addresses (NYHS-RG 11) for correspondence of 1865-1866 related to the original score.
- Emma Thursby Celebration., 1940 December (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  Includes invitations, correspondence (acceptances and regrets), and event programs.
- Harry T. Peters Reception, 1942 March (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  Includes a small number of acceptances and regrets for a reception for lecturer Peters.
- Odell Reception. Invitations and Event Program, 1942 October 23 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
- Odell Reception. Correspondence, General (1 of 2), 1942 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
- Odell Reception. Correspondence, General (2 of 2), 1942 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
- Odell Reception. Invitation Lists, 1942 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
- Odell Reception. Invitation Contact Information, 1942 (Offsite-box 14, Cards -)
  Includes unused tickets to N-YHS events of September 1941-June 1942 repurposed as index cards, with contact information for potential invitees to the Odell event written on the back of the tickets.
- Odell Reception. Correspondence, Acceptances (1 of 2), 1942 October (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
- Odell Reception. Correspondence, Acceptances (2 of 2), 1942 October (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
- Odell Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (1 of 2), 1942 October (Offsite-box 11, Folder 7)
- Odell Reception. Correspondence, Regrets (2 of 2), 1942 October (Offsite-box 11, Folder 8)
- Odell Reception. Walter Hampden Address, 1942 November (Offsite-box 11, Folder 9)
  Includes Hampden's remarks at the Odell event as recorded by the stenographer, with Hampden's edits.
- Odell Reception. Typescript of Proceedings, 1942 October 23 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 10)
  Includes the remarks made at the event as recorded by the Stenotype Recording Company. Speakers include: George A. Zabriskie, Millard L. Robinson, Joseph Wood Krutch, Arthur Hobson Quinn, Walter Hampden, Walter Prichard Eaton, William Lyons Phelps, letter read from Nicholas Murray Butler, and George Clinton Densmore Odell.
- Odell Reception. Correspondence, Distribution of Proceedings, 1943 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 11)
- Opening of Early American Rooms. Correspondence, Acceptances (1 of 3), 1951 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
- Opening of Early American Rooms. Correspondence, Acceptances (2 of 3), 1951 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
- Opening of Early American Rooms. Correspondence, Acceptances (3 of 3), 1951 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
- Opening of Early American Rooms. Correspondence, Regrets (1 of 3), 1951 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
- Opening of Early American Rooms. Correspondence, Regrets (2 of 3), 1951 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
- Opening of Early American Rooms. Correspondence, Regrets (3 of 3), 1951 May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Arrangements Committee, 1952-1953 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Dinner Invitations, Menu, Program, Lists, 1954 March-May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 8)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Correspondence, Dinner Acceptances, 1954 April-May (Offsite-box 12, Folder 9)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Correspondence, Dinner Regrets, 1954 April (Offsite-box 12, Folder 10)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Dinner Remarks by Fenwick Beekman, 1954 May 3 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 11)
  Includes N-YHS President Beekman's remarks introducing speaker Grayson L. Kirk.
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Meeting Invitations and Program, 1954 November 19 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 12)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Meeting Ticket Requests, 1954 November (Offsite-box 13, Cards -)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Correspondence, Regrets, 1954 November (Offsite-box 12, Folder 13)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Meeting Ticket Distribution Lists, 1954 November (Offsite-box 12, Folder 14)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Meeting Remarks of Fenwick Beekman, [1954 November 19] (Offsite-box 12, Folder 15)
  See also New-York Historical Society manuscripts of lectures and addresses (NYHS-RG 11) for a manuscript copy of Allan Nevins's address at this event, titled "The Golden Thread in the History of New York."
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Miscellaneous, 1954 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 16)
  Includes the offering brochure for purchases of the sesqui-centennial medal, an award of merit to N-YHS from the American Association for State and Local History, and invoices.
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Commemorative Medal (2), 1954 (Offsite-box 13, Envelope 1)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Steel Stamp, 1954 (Offsite-box 13, Envelope 2)
- Sesqui-Centennial (150th) Anniversary. Oversize, 1953-1954 (Box OS-1, Folder 6)
  Includes correspondence concerning the Commemorative Medal and a poster board from 1954 signed by the N-YHS staff.
- Excess Ephemera (Restricted), 1870, 1877, 1904, 1939 (Offsite-box 16)
  This box includes only excess copies of tickets and other ephemera culled from the folders in the record group. Events represented in the box are: 66th Anniversary/Charles Francis Adams address, 100th Anniversary of the New York State Constitution/Charles O'Conor address, N-YHS Centennial Banquet, and "Sancte Claus, Goed Heylig Man!" facsimile score. Because the material is redundant it is available for internal use only.